<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UbuntuServer on Tipnmog Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ubuntuserver/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UbuntuServer on Tipnmog Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ubuntuserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Website from GoDaddy Hosting to Digital Ocean VPS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/godaddy-hosting-to-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/godaddy-hosting-to-vps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be a documentation of moving a website from GoDaddy shared hosting to Digital Ocean droplet.  Any other cloud hosting service should work with variation in the server creation on the cloud system.  For example other services such as Linode etc.  Note that Digital Ocean calls their virtual machines droplets, other providers will have a different name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While documenting this process I moved the domain 09flhrc.com from GoDaddy shared hosting to a Digital Ocean Droplet.  The IP address assigned to the droplet is 143.110.204.149&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncomplicated Fire Wall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux_ufw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux_ufw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Linux kernel includes the &lt;strong&gt;Netfilter&lt;/strong&gt; subsystem, which is used to manipulate or decide the fate of network traffic headed into or through your server. All modern Linux firewall solutions use this system for packet filtering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kernel’s packet filtering system would be of little use to administrators without a userspace interface to manage it. This is the purpose of the &lt;code&gt;**iptables**&lt;/code&gt; utility: when a packet reaches your server, it will be handed off to the Netfilter subsystem for acceptance, manipulation, or rejection based on the rules supplied to it from the userspace (via &lt;code&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt;). Thus, &lt;code&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt; is all you need to manage your firewall, if you’re familiar with it, but many are available to simplify the task. We’ll take a look at the default frontend used in Ubuntu here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
